Jamel Lawson

708-833-9788 • lawson.jamel@yahoo.com

Talented Web Developer & Software Engineer

Skilled web developer and software engineer with degree in Computer Science and understanding of real-world business objectives and how they apply to projects. Capable of working on projects of any size from small tasks to enterprise level projects. Demonstrated experience with architecture, coding, database programming and QA efforts. Consummate team player who exhibits initiative and communication skills when working in team environment. Areas of skill and focus include:

Web Development/Coding Client/Server Architecture Quality Assurance

Software Engineering/Coding

N-Tier Architecture

Systems Analysis / Needs Analysis

Responsive & Mobile Web Design Database Programming Requirements Gathering

Object Oriented Programming Project & SDLC Management Cross Functional Collaboration

Software & Programming Languages

Adobe Dreamweaver & Photoshop	SQL (MySQL & MS SQL Server)	Sass & Compass

Adobe Illustrator & InDesign PHP / Java / Python / xcode JavaScript / AJAX / jQuery / JSON

Eclipse Android Studio HTML5 / HTML / XHTML / XML Drupal Microsoft Office Cascading Style Sheets (CSS3) GitHub

Education & Training

Android Mobile Development Certification Program, University of Maryland	In Progress
Bachelor of Science in Informatics w/Art Cognate, University of Iowa	2013

Relevant Experience

NRH Works LLC, Champaign, IL

Web Developer

2014-Present

Collaborate with project teams to create responsive websites and/or email templates using HTML5, HTML, and CSS that keep a consistent user experience across multiple browsers, platforms, and viewports. Create sites from provided Photoshop files, test code, and troubleshoot errors. Monitor the performance of and maintain client websites as directed.

• Contributed to the successful completion of projects for Johns Hopkins University and Origin Bank

University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA

Computer Lab Tutor

2013

Leverage knowledge of and experience with Java, Python, and HTML to support fellow students in computer lab environment. Assist with identifying errors, suggesting improved logic, and developing effective coding habits.

Iowa City Middle School, Iowa City, IA

Software Developer

2012

Designed and deployed a module for a learning application used by middle school students. Reviewed needs, gathered requirements, planned scopes of work and ensured applications met business objectives. Utilized xcode (objective-C) to create a functional and aesthetically appealing software application for the Apple iPad.

Additional Experience

University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA	Parking & Transportation Cashier	2012 - 2013
University of Iowa Foundation, Iowa City, IA	Telefund Specialist	2010 - 2011